<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Millenial Lifehacker</title>
    <description>I run, I travel, and I tinker. This site was created to capture all of those moments.
</description>
    <link>http://ericreichert.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ericreichert.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 15:23:21 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 15:23:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brandam idea</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have this great idea that a friend and I came up with that I’m excited to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ericreichert.com/2015/12/31/BrandAm-Idea.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ericreichert.com/2015/12/31/BrandAm-Idea.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving from Wordpress to Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a post about &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; love for &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello this is a test.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ericreichert.com/2015/12/31/Moving-from-Wordpress-to-Jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ericreichert.com/2015/12/31/Moving-from-Wordpress-to-Jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 23:40:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ericreichert.com/jekyll/update/2015/12/30/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ericreichert.com/jekyll/update/2015/12/30/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ich bin Berliner</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Kennedy may have said it wrong, but Dan and I made sure we wouldn’t make the same mistake. To even call it a mistake is slighting Kennedy. We were able to see the history and the city where he made one of his most iconic speeches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Berlin is a dynamic location, it is full of history but manages to stay current as well. The first thing you’ll realize about Berlin is that it isn’t built the same way our cities are in the US. You won’t find Sky Scrapers or  many buildings with more than 10 floors. The highest points are either church steeples or TV towers. However, just because there aren’t many tall buildings does not mean the buildings lack grandeur. The architecture and attention to detail is beautiful. These buildings weren’t constructed in a few years, they are works of art in themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My journey to Berlin started on Wednesdays night, when I made my way to Dan’s apartment to spend the night. Their apartments are only a ten minute walk to the train station, so it makes sense to stay with them when I’m travelling. My plan for the weekend was to board a train on Thursday morning, arrive in Berlin, find my hostel, and then explore. Dan and Julio were planning to meet me Friday night since they didn’t have the same regional holiday I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday and Friday were essentially days that I was on my own. So naturally, I made sure to use the most of them! I travelled everywhere by foot and had my bearings by the end of the first night. On Thursday, I took a lot of pictures and visited a lot of stores. Since Berlin was the first big city I had visited in Germany, it was my first opportunity to see what the stores were like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked throughout a mall or two and was quite impressed by the selections that they had in Germany. Most of the companies I had never head of, but they also had some of the bigger brands that I’d image you’d find anywhere. Within a H&amp;amp;M store, I found two shirts that I purchased. One was a white boating shirt and the other was a long sleeve pullover. I liked the styles and imagine it would be hard to find them in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I was bored walking through malls, I decided I wanted to see some history. When I had walked from the train station to my hostel I had passed a few museums that interested me. One in particular was the Pergamon Museum. Fall semester of my junior year, I took an Art History class that detailed some of the art work within this museum. I had remembered the name and instantly knew that the Ishtar gate was inside. I made my way from the mall to the museum and paid entry (It was cheaper for me since I’m a student). There were various friezes and mosaic tiled floor arrangements. However, for me, seeing the Ishtar gate was the highlight. The craftsmanship involved in created that, literally blows my mind. You can easily see with your eyes the detail and time that was spent creating it. I find it harder to see such craftsmanship in today’s society … but I have also yet to travel to Dubai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I finished touring the Pergamon Museum, I travelled to the Berliner Döm. This building alone made my trip to Berlin worth it for me. I sat in front of the Berliner Döm for about an hour just appreciating it. It has a fountain directly in front of it that makes the environment soothing. You are able to see the Berliner Döm from most places near the Alexander Platz. Colin Lynch would be proud because I used this location to read the book he gave me, The Rising Sun. I wish that I had a place like the Berliner Döm in Blomberg so that I could go there everyday to read and relax. I suppose I’ll just have to find a place of my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading for about an hour, I decided that it was time to meet some other travellers. So, naturally I headed to the bar in my hostel. I managed to meet someone from Liverpool that was also travelling alone. He had travelled for about a week but was going to continue travelling for what seemed like months. We both decided that we would meet up the next day and tour some more sights. The same night at the bar I met 3 girls from Ireland, 3 guys from Switzerland, and a group of people from Poland. The hostel was a trendy establishment and not quite what I had pictured. I might have just been lucky with the weekend I was there, but all the people were friendly and open-minded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, Ian and I grabbed breakfast at 10:00 and then hit the city. We navigated our way to the Brandenburg Gate, British Consulate, and a few stores for shopping. The previous day, Ian had dropped his phone in the elevator and his battery had fallen down the shaft… now that is bad luck. Luckily, we were able to find him a replacement in the electronics store Saturn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I’m going to say about Saturn is that it was Geek heaven. There were 4 floors worth of electronics and they literally had everything you could imagine..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Ian and I toured the sites and grabbed some food, we made our way back to the hostel. I had told Dan and Julio that I would meet him there that night and since I had no way of contacting them, it was important that I stayed true to my word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you saw part one in the title, you knew that this blog post was eventually going to split up … and that point is now. Part two will encompass the point when I met my guest(s) later on that night…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope that are enjoying my posts! Leave a comment and let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ericreichert.com/2011/07/06/ich-bin-berliner.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ericreichert.com/2011/07/06/ich-bin-berliner.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Differences between Germany and USA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For this blog post, I thought I’d branch out in another direction. I know that before I came to Germany the main thing I was doing was preparing for all the change. I was trying to make sure that my transition would be smooth … and it has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there were a lot more minor differences that I’ve noticed that I didn’t expect. Being cultured means that I can accept the difference and then form an unbiased opinion. It hasn’t been hard to accept the changes, because front my point of view, most of them have been for the better; improvements if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So.. what you’ve been waiting for, my list. I’ll go into detail when I find it fitting. I’ve gone ahead and ordered the list by most expected to least expected, so some of the ones at the top will be quite obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Language
Money
Outlets for devices
Drinking age
Metric System
Shops closed on Sunday
The aforementioned list I expected .. it’s the following that I did not :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shopping carts
You insert a Euro coin every time that you use one, once you put the cart away it gives you your Euro back. Smart!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hole punches in paper
Not sure why but there are only two holes instead of three… and they are located towards the middle of the page. Then again, I’m really not sure why we have 3 in America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direction doors open
For some reason I’m an idiot when it comes to opening doors in Germany. Apparently the direction they open depends on whether the area is part of an escape route. I didn’t realize how nice those bars are that we push when exiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flushing toilets
There are two buttons, I have no clue what the difference is between them.. I pick at random each time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic light locations
Instead of being across the street from where you stop, they are right in front of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recycling
Germans are quite particular when it comes to recycling, everything has to be in a certain color bag and so forth..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way windows open
Windows might be like this in the US too, but here when you twist the handle so it is up and down, the window comes towards you like it is falling. Not going to lie.. was pretty scared today when I thought a huge window was going to crush me, my colleagues laughed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyboards - Y and Z are switched
I have no clue why they are switched, it’s a curveball every day. Never realized how much I use those two letters. Just used them 5 times in this past sentence…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bathrooms at Fast Food places
You need to have a pass code that is located on your receipt… SMART!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entrance/Exit in stores
I feel like some of the stores are like Ikea, I have to walk through the whole thing and then the cash register area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breakfast
They do it big in Germany, apparently they actually structure there meals like your suppose to eat them. The emphasis is on breakfast instead of dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drinking in public
It’s fair game… shocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concludes my blog for today, hope that you learned a thing or two about Germany. If there is anything else you’d like to know, don’t hesitate to leave a comment. I appreciate all of you that are reading and hope that you enjoy doing so. Tell me what you think!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ericreichert.com/2011/06/20/differences-between-germany-and-usa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ericreichert.com/2011/06/20/differences-between-germany-and-usa.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Schuetzen Fest</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll start this blog off by briefly describing what Schützenfest exactly is. Quite simply, it’s a marksman’s festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year there is a celebration where people gather to witness people compete based on their shooting skills. The winner of the competition in most cases, is the marksman who is able to shoot and hit the wooden eagle. He is then crowned the Schützenkonig and remains so until the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I went to this Schützenfest with Sven, Dan, and Julio, we did not see any of the actual shooting. Instead we witnessed the parade, fair, and after party. The whole celebration was stunning and wouldn’t be likened to anything in the US. After the parade, we all made our way to the tent where people drink and converse throughout the day. Apparently, the celebration lasts until the next morning and is then followed by a large breakfast. I’m starting to get the idea that most German holidays revolve around food and drinking, but I suppose they do everywhere. The difference is that the Germans can hold their alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as my group, we had 3 or 4 beers over a couple of hours and then biked to another beer garden where they had Weiss Beer.  As far as Weiss Beer goes, I had my first and may have had my last. It was a very heavy drink and almost felt like it shouldn’t be a fluid. I suppose only real men drink Weiss Beer, I also suppose I’m not a real man yet…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I’m glad that we trekked our way to the festival and would be sure to go again. Luckily enough for me, Schützenfest takes place in different towns on different dates. The Schützenfest that most people know of takes place in Hannover and holds the fame for having the largest parade and largest portable ferris wheel in the world.  Sadly, this festival takes place in September, so I will no longer be within Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m beginning to feel cultured and am enjoying learning about the traditions and heritage of Germany!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ericreichert.com/2011/06/15/schuetzen-fest.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ericreichert.com/2011/06/15/schuetzen-fest.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hannover Havoc</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I may have mentioned in an earlier blog, that I am now a world traveller … that statement was false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to travelling, it is quite clear that I have a lot to learn. This past weekend, myself and two other colleagues decided to embark on an adventure to the city of Hannover. It is the largest city within an hour of our work, so we found it a fitting trip for our first friday night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose this story starts on Friday at 17:00, when I left work to head home. Since it was the weekend, it meant it was my first opportunity to borrow a car from the company and venture out of the roads of Germany. I know the first thing you are all thinking … AUTOBAHN! Sadly, I had no need to travel on the autobahn , so I’ll have to save that for another trip. But, I still had to navigate myself home from work and to an uncharted area. I managed well and was able to do so because I briefly brushed up on the signage before leaving work that day. You’d think that most things are universal no matter where you’d go, and you’d be right to a certain extent. However, it is the subtleties that are the difference between safe driving and a totalled car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I left work, I headed home to quickly pack a few items and then headed towards Bad Pyrmont, my first stop for the night. When I arrived, I was greeted by two colleagues (Dan Fenton and Julio Compean). They showed me around their apartments and treated me to my third beer in Germany. It was a Schwarze Bier (translated into Black Bier) so naturally it was a darker brew. I explained to them that I hadn’t eaten in a while and that I could go for a quick bite to eat before we left for Hannover. With ease, they were able to recommend the local Beer Garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I knew it, I was tasting an authentic German meal paired with a Löwenbräu, my Dad’s favorite. We were outside enjoying the weather and conversation when we noticed that it was going to be close to catch the train. We paid quickly and all started sprinting … towards nowhere. We soon realized that we had become a bit disoriented and weren’t sure which direction the train station was. After we asked a local, we had our bearings and were able to head out for the night. We made it to the train station, or rather .. I made it to the train station just as it was leaving. Julio and Dan had used better judgement and started walking when they realized what time it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the themes during this trip that you’ll soon realize was our groups ability to “be so close, but so far”. For the next hour, the three of us purchased our train tickets and chatted about various topics. These conversations were spoken in “Denglish”, which I previously described. Julio was luckily enough to had lived in Germany for a year before this experience, which is helpful for Dan and me, because he is able to fine tune our grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This meant that we would have to spend the night in Hannover;a speed bump but not a major problem. We all walked back to the lockers and found the one in which we had stowed away all of our bags. I beckoned to Julio, “ The key please..”. He quickly searched all of his pockets and began to look dumbfounded. Dan and I at this point realized that our problems were growing. We all began to search our pockets to make sure that we hadn’t somehow wound up with the key. No luck.Once we boarded the train it was only about an hour to Hannover. The train ride went by quickly and we made it to the station without any hitches. When we arrived in Hannover, we decided that it’d be best to stow away our bags in one of the train station lockers, so we did so. Julio pocketed the key to the locker and we were off to explore. There were a lot of people walking around the town and the sky still glowed from the sun as it set. We made our way through various shopping malls and ultimately found a small club in the city square. We entered and were greeted by peers of our own ages, shocking compared to most of the club life in the states, or so I’ve heard. The music was blaring and the environment was engaging. Julio and I set our jackets down on a stool sitting next to Dan and proceeded on to the dance floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few hours of hearing songs I did know and didn’t know, we all decided that we had enough fun dancing and would begin to head back to Bad Pyrmont. This was the point where our troubles seemed to exponentially grow. We headed back to the train station to only when arrived that we were a half hour late to making the last train home to Bad Pyrmont…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within an hour, we were without a train and without all of our stuff. Thankfully, I chose to keep everything important on me (i.e. my passport, keys, camera). The next two hours, we traced all of our steps to see if we had somehow dropped the key along our adventure. No luck. We soon realized that we would have to go to the information desk and report our key as missing. When we did so, they told us that we would have to wait until 7am to speak with the people who were in charge of the lockers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of our night was spent in the McDonalds within the train station. We wouldn’t have had enough money or passports to have gotten a hotel room, so we had limited options. Staying within McDonalds was a superb decision. Julio and Dan slept as I watched all the other people come in after they had left other clubs. Before you start thinking that we were in the slums of some city, vulnerable to the wrath of mischievousness, let me explain where we were located. If I had to describe the place, I’d liken the train station  to a mall and the mcdonalds to a food court. We were certainly out of harms way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EAhBLRsxJHw&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When seven o’ clock rolled around, I was somehow still wide awake and ready to head back to Bad Pyrmont. (This might be proof that my body still has no clue what time it is.) We made our way to the information desk and were then greeted by the official in charge of lockers. After explaining the  contents of the locker, showing identification, and paying a 25 euro replacement key fee …. we had our bags. At that point, I was wondering if my t-shirt and shorts in the bag were worth the 8 euros I had just chipped in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we had our bags, we proceeded to buy our train tickets. I looked at the ticket and figured out that we needed to be standing on the second track and that our train would leave in 5 minutes. Before I headed to track 2, Julio looked at the sign and saw a town near ours and realized we needed to actually be on track 1. Close call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We boarded the train and sat down relaxing for the first time within a few hours. We were finally about to make our way back to Bad Pyrmont and this adventure would be over. I remember closing my eyes and thinking about all the obstacles we had encountered the previous night. &lt;em&gt;Nudge&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Nudge&lt;/em&gt; Next thing I realize is that I’m being awoken by a man from the UBahn. No big deal I thought to myself, my train ticket is right here in my pocket. I reached in my pocket grabbed the ticket and handed it to the man. At this moment I realized he looked a bit timid. He looked down at me and said to me in German, “Wrong train.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I thought to myself was track 2. Shoot! I knew that I had looked at the right listing and that we were not again, not where we wanted to be. He ushered us of the train and explained to us that in an hour another train would come and take us the rest of the way to Bad Pyrmont. I remember thinking to myself, sure it will. Knowing our luck, somehow the train will break down and we’ll have to walk the rest of the way. This didn’t wind up happening, but something else did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan and Julio walked off the train with me and proceeded to the benches at the station. I walked over to the arrival/departure board to figure out what train we had to catch. After triple checking myself, I learned that our next train was going to come at 8:41. It was now 8:00 and a brisk morning. I sat down in between Julio and Dan and laughed to myself, I thought, “Well, I suppose this is what travelling is like for everyone.” Thinking about it now, hopefully it’s not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I knew it, it was 8:41 and our train had come. A very long train arrived in front of us and stopped completely. I looked up at the destination  before entering and thought it was odd that it still displayed Hammeln, the name of the station that we were now at. We sat down and began to get comfortable when we realized that all the other people at the station hadn’t boarded anywhere near us. Again, odd. It wasn’t until a women quickly ran over and approached us that I realized that the long train was in fact two trains. The one that we were sitting in, wasn’t going to be leaving the station, it was stopped. After feeling like a complete and utter idiot, we quickly ran over to the other train and boarded in just a nick of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully… thankfully, that was our last hiccup. From Hammeln, the train took us to Bad Pyrmont, where we were able to walk back to the apartment and take a nap for a good seven hours. Our adventure was over and our night would forever be known as Hannover Havoc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ericreichert.com/2011/06/14/hannover-havoc.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ericreichert.com/2011/06/14/hannover-havoc.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hannover Reloaded, Warburg, and Wine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As promised, this post will be about our second trip to Hannover (hence the Hannover Reloaded), our trip to Warburg, and the wine festival in Bad Pyrmont. All of the events detailed in this post took place in June from the 17th to 19th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story starts on the 17th after I finished work for the day. Since we are able to make our own hours in Germany, I front-loaded the week so that I could get off by 15:00 to head home and pack. I was able to make it to Bad Pyrmont to meet up with Dan and Julio for dinner. Once again, we were planning our weekend last-minute and had no clue what we wanted to do. The only thing we knew was how the Bahn pricing worked, with this information we were able to decide where we could go within our price limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had already agreed to meet Zach Mitchell, a friend from college, the next day in Warburg. So with this information, we knew we either needed to go to somewhere within the same region or buy a schoneswochenende ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this ticket, you are able to travel anywhere in Germany from 0:00 the day you buy it to 03:00 the next morning. So naturally, we decided we would buy the Schoneswochenende ticket and leave for Hannover at midnight … yet again. However, after miserably failing the first time we attempted this, we were quite optimistic that this time would go more smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were right, for once. The three of us were able to navigate to Hannover without any problem, make it back to the same discotec that we had gone to before, and navigate home the next morning without missing any trains. Most importantly, we were able to do this all with one ticket. Unlike the first time when we had to keep buying them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived back at Julio’s apartment at roughly 08:00 on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was to sleep for 3 hours and then catch another train to Warburg so that we could meet up with my friend Zach. Put simply, Julio didn’t wake up. So the trio became a duo and we were off for Warburg. Suprisingly, I was not too tired after only have a few hours to sleep. In the back of my mind I knew that Sunday was going to hurt, but at that time I was still thinking about Saturday. Without too much confusion, Dan and I made it to Warburg and were greeted by Zach on the platform. Instantously, we were again a trio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turned out, there wasn’t much to do in Warburg on the Saturday that we arrived. Most of the shops were closed and the streets were empty. We concluded that it must have been some sort of regional holiday. However, we were able to find a Wurst Shop that was open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the shop, we were able to try Curry Wurst, the local beer, and french fries with Mayo. It was all scrumptious. We then made our way through the town, stopped at an icecream shop, and grabbed a six-pack for the road. We made camp at a trail that we found and were able to have riveting conversation about the Greek economy, German Health Care, and what we hoped to carry out while in Germany. It was nice to talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then proceeded back to the train station so that we could all catch our trains back home. Dan and I made it back to Julio’s apartment within two hours and were greeted by a well rested Julio. He was ready for some adventure of his own, so his coaxed Dan and I to embark on yet another adventure. This time we wouldn’t be taking any trains, we were just navigating our way to the local wine festival. We walked around there for about ten minutes and then were able to find a nice white wine for only 10€ a bottle. We bought three bottles and then went back to Julio’s to relax for the rest of the night. We watched a Jim Carey movie in German and passed out for the next 12 hours. The sleep was much-needed and appreciated, even though I had slept on the floor of Julio’s apartment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weekend was thrilling, spontaneous, and long. I navigated back to my house on Sunday and didn’t do much of anything. I went for my run, did some laundry, and slept. It was mainly a day of rest, exactly what Sunday should be!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next blog post will detail my 4 day trip to Berlin. It will encompass some of the people I met, the places I went, and the things I bought! Hope you enjoy reading my blogs, because I enjoy reliving them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ericreichert.com/2011/06/12/hannover-reloaded-warburg-and-wine.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ericreichert.com/2011/06/12/hannover-reloaded-warburg-and-wine.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My First Week in Germany</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to believe that I’ve already been in Germany for a week. It might have something to do with the fact that I’ve been half asleep the whole time. Jetlag is a beast of its own and has thoroughly confused my body until recently. My running coach, Coach Falk, told me that every timezone you go through takes about a day for your body to recover, I now concur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a week of changes and firsts, I’m starting to feel settled. Everything is unpacked and has a place. My day is starting to become rhythmic and this is good since I like routine. I’m getting accustomed to the hours of work and the general region in which I’m living. If you were to look at the photos within my album on Facebook, entitled Germany Eins, you’d see the my house in the quaint town of Hershey is far different from my house in Leopoldstal, Germany. When I walk out my door every morning, I don’t see other cars or other houses, I see cows and running trails. Don’t get me wrong, this is great .. it’s just different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll walk you through a day in my life, this past week. Every morning I rise at 6:00am so that I’m able to get a quick shower, dressed, and a small bite to eat. At 6:40am, I walk outside my front door to meet my neighbor and his two daughters. His name is Sven and his daughters are Jenny and Vanessa. Each day, we then drive two minutes to drop Jenny off for the bus and then another minute to drop Vanessa off for the train. This is followed by a 15 minute drive to Blomberg, where Sven and I talk about vocabulary and what we will carry out that day. The drive is scenic and a good way to start the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrive at work around 7:00am and then make my way to building 14. After I hike my way to the third floor Key Account Management section of the building, I am able to start my day. For the first week, a glass of Apfelsaftschorle and bread with cheese accompanied me during the morning. I ate for the second time in the morning to ensure that my body would stay awake and that I was nourished. It seemed to do the trick, keeping me awake and productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first week, I was assigned my seven projects, given a company orientation, and treated to meals several times. All the people within my department were very welcoming and anxious to learn about me. I realized that the trip would be a two-way road since they were appreciative that I brought new skills to the table. Most of my work during this summer will be on a process improvement basis. I will be analyzing the systems they use to complete various tasks and search for cheaper, quicker, more effective ways to do them. They hope that I bring experience and knowledge from the systems are effectively seen within the US subsidiary. Hopefully I will not disappoint by the end of my stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 12:00pm everyday, a few colleagues and myself take a two-minute trek over to the company cafeteria. Within the cafeteria there is an ATM, where I’m able to withdrawal money, as well as tons of meal options, of course! The meals are all priced around 4 to five Euro which is about equal to what I’d pay for lunch in the US. Most employees only eat lunch for about a half hour so that they can get out the door quicker at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many perks to the company in Germany in comparison to in the USA. For instance, each employee has a card that they scan upon entering the building. This card doubles as a timecard and a debit card for lunch. It keeps track of your weekly hours which allows people to essentially make their own hours. If someone wants to come in at 6 and leave at 3, they can. It is quite empowering to the employees to have the freedom to build their own hours. Another benefit is that if an employee works longer nights and works more than their 40 hours for the week, it is then added to their vacation. However, some employees have 100 hours of vacation and no time to spend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch each day, I head back to my workstation to finish out the last three hours or so hours of my day. All of the people within my department are quite friendly to me and are willing to help me with my German. At first, we were speaking predominantly german but that became a little overwhelming. Now, they speak a sort of Denglish (Deutsch and English) to me. I try to respond in German unless I don’t have the vocabulary. I’m starting to feel much more confident with my speaking and hope that my grammar grows as exponentially as my vocabulary is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of each day I head back to the front gate of the building and meet my neighbor Sven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then drive back to our house and discuss if we will make plans for the rest of the night. So far, he has taken me to the grocery store one night, to a local city known as Detmold, and out for ice cream. I’m very fortunate to have helpful people surrounding me at work and at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each night is when I have my opportunities to explore. However, for most of the first week I was trying to get settled. I did manage to go for a run, a two-hour bike ride, and for some local exploration. Starting on Monday I’m going to begin to start training regularly again and prepare for Cross Country. There are limitless trails surrounding my house that will accommodate for all of my needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there are any things that you’d wish I’d elaborate on, make sure to leave a comment below illustrating what you’d like. My next post will be about my trip to Hannover on friday and the adventure that unfolded. The story is one of a kind and will surely be a good read, but until then tschuss!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ericreichert.com/2011/06/12/my-first-week-in-germany.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ericreichert.com/2011/06/12/my-first-week-in-germany.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sprechen sie Deutsch?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ja, ein bischen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard that phrase and given that response in countless occasions during the past few days. Another colleague of mine said that our immersion should be likened to more of a drowning rather than “get your toes wet”. Right when I arrived in Germany I realized the grandeur of this adventure. I literally hadn’t given the trip any thought, I was trying to not get excited. If I wasn’t excited, I couldn’t be disappointed, that was my train of thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m here, wow.. As I was saying, the moment I stepped off the airplane I realized that I was on my own. I had a train ticket in my hand that was entirely written in German, that I had only looked at ONCE. Poor planning on my part I suppose. But, nevertheless, I still managed to make it to my first train. I arrived there thinking that I would just grab a seat on a train like in America. This was when I realized something, I wasn’t in America. Just as all my cultural classes had taught me, things were quite different. I looked over my ticket again briefly and realized that printed on the ticket were a couple of numbers, one signified the cart and the other the seat. This was a tremendous find on my part, 30 seconds before the train arrived. I had diverted a lot of awkward conversation that ultimately could have caused me to miss the train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I boarded the first train, I was a world traveller. I had successfully departed a plane and boarded on a train. Boy did I feel accomplished, … or shall I say relieved. The train brought me to a main train station in Frankfurt where I was able to board another train that would ultimately take me to Kassel. The train ride was my first moment where I could relax. I didn’t have to worry about getting enough sleep on the plane, or finding my bags in time to board the train. I was able to absorb the scenery and the dynamic culture of Germany. After an hour of sight-seeing, I was on to the next stop of my adventure, the Taxi ride to my house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The taxi driver was standing in the building, outside the platform, holding an iPad 2 with Phoenix Contact on it. I looked around, decided that he was here for me and proceeded towards him. He greeted me with, “Guten tag Herr Reichert, wie gehts?” At that moment, I had my first opportunity to use the little language I knew. I answered modestly, “ Ich bin sehr gut!” Speaking German in a class room setting is far easier than speaking to a native German. Most of the time, the person you’re speaking to has a similarly limited vocabulary and you are almost able to know what they will respond. However, in the real world, there are no limits. Germans have vocabularies with the sky being their limit, just as people do all around the world. In a classroom, you are almost oblivious to it. There are no curveballs, there is merely the next regularly accepted response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train ride from Kassel to Leopaldstahn was thrilling. It was my first time on the Autobahn and my first time in a car that was going over 100mphs … legally. The signage (Zaechen) in Germany is far different from in America, which makes me a little hesitant to get behind the wheel over here. I will only have access to a car on the weekend, but I’m going to make sure I understand everything about German traffic (Verkehr) before I get on the road. It is experiences like the taxi ride that make learning fun, I was able to pick up a couple of words in an environment that was tied to a memory. It allowed me the opportunity to learn a word … for good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived at my house in Leopaldstahn it was just like the pictures I had seen on the website; it was breathtaking. The area is located in the country and there are numerous running trails placed closely to my house. The site is ideal for a person working in a city that needs the chance to retreat to a home for relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… which is shown in the screenshot below:
&lt;img src=&quot;http://ericreichert.com/assets/german-house.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my next post, I’ll be sure to go in-depth to how my first few days were and what type of experiences I encountered. I’ll post a few photos on here with the bulk of them being posted on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, tschuss!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ericreichert.com/2011/06/08/Sprechen-sie-Deutsch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ericreichert.com/2011/06/08/Sprechen-sie-Deutsch.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
